<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chrome on a flash of light and a distant boom.</title>
    <link>http://blog.soulshake.net/tags/chrome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chrome on a flash of light and a distant boom.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.soulshake.net/tags/chrome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Weird zooming after changing tabs in Chromium on Debian with i3</title>
      <link>http://blog.soulshake.net/post/scroll-rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.soulshake.net/post/scroll-rage/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after switching from OSX, I noticed that I would get unexpected (and extremely annoying) zooming after changing tabs in Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, it became apparent that it only happened when I had scrolled up or down just before changing tabs with Ctrl Up/Down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the steps to reproduce were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scroll a bit in tab A (the faster the scroll, the longer the coast)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;while tab A is still coasting, change tabs to tab B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is if you had pressed &lt;code&gt;ctrl+=&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ctrl+-&lt;/code&gt; a bunch of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fooling around with &lt;code&gt;xinput&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xev&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xserver-xorg-input-synaptics&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xorg.conf&lt;/code&gt;, etc, I realized the scrolling/coasting action was being interpreted as keypresses even after changing contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt-get install xserver-xorg-input-synaptics
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package provides &lt;code&gt;synclient&lt;/code&gt;, a commandline utility to query and modify Synaptics driver options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The culprit was the default settings for the Synaptics touchpad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ synclient -l | grep -i coast
CornerCoasting          = 0
CoastingSpeed           = 20
CoastingFriction        = 50
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played with the settings until I found a combination that allowed a reasonable amount of coasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing CoastingSpeed to 0 disabled the smooth scrolling effect-thing completely. Any value higher than 0, and the behavior was still present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing &lt;code&gt;CoastingFriction&lt;/code&gt; to 255 slowed down the scrolling effect enough so that the coasting would stop before I could change tabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr:93c9f1c2744e6c23bcf7cbb7379abb5b&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;xserver-xorg-input-synaptics&lt;/code&gt; and add the following lines to your profile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CoastingSpeed           = 10
CoastingFriction        = 255
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, much better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>